<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <!-- Mythic Item Descriptions -->
    <!-- Mythic Weapon Descriptions -->

    <string name="mythw_desc_1">
        These two items are always found together;
        they were obviously part of some ancient panoply from a forgotten time.
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_2">
        This black-bladed dagger will only reveal its magical powers when used
        by a person with a Luck of 13+.
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_3">
        The magical virtues of this bow can only be used by the most Graceful warriors
        or specialists (i.e. those with a grace of 13+).
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_4">
        In addition to their normal damage, these arrows cause the target to either fall
        in love or become jealous of another person or creature - unless the target makes
        a Mystic Fortitude saving roll.
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_5">
        This javelin allows Graceful Warriors (i.e. those with a Grace Score of 13+)
        to add their Grace bonus to both their Missile attack roll and damage roll.
        Note, however that the Javelin of Heartbreak cannot be used as a melee spear. (Enc=1)
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_6">
        The magical virtues of this spear can only be used by classic Amazons (or by alternate
        Amazons with a grace of 13+). It allows the wielder to add her Grace bonus to her
        Initiative and Melee attack roll when the soear is used to Charge into Battle. (Enc=2)
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_7">
        This magical spear can only be properly used by Hunters; its magical properties can only
        operate against Beasts and Monsters. When used in Melee, it allows the Hunter to benefit
        from his Skill-based damage bonus; when thrown as a javelin, it doubles this damage bonus (Enc=2)
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_8">
        This magical spear grants its user a bonus to his Melee attacks and damage rolls when used
        against Monsters. This bonus varies according to the size of the creature (the bigger the better!):
        +1 if Medium or smaller, +2 if Large and +4 if Gigantic.
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_9">
        Created as a gift for the Noble divine agents of Aphrodite, this sword can only be used by Graceful
        warriors (i.e. with a Grace of 13+), allowing them to add their Grace mod to damage rolls (Enc=1)
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_10">
        This ancient magical bronze sword grants a +2 bonus to Melee and damage when used against Minotaurs
        and other true Minotaur-kin, as well as against bulls including Giant and Magical ones but excluding Bronze Animates
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_11">
        These ancient short swords were used by the men of King Letos, first monarch of Thena in their battles against the ophidian
        minions of Thulsos
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_12">
        This unique, beautifully-crafted and indestructible two-handed battle axe was forged at the dawn of the Age of Magic as a
        symbol of royalty for the kings of the Uroks - the creatures humans prefer to refer to as Golden Minotaurs.
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_13">
        This weapon can launch as many Fiery Darts (as per the Elementalist power of the same name) per day as the character\'s
        Melee mod. it can also be used as a normal sword.
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_14">
        The spear of Vapor when thrown by a character with a Skill of 13 or higher, turns into a vaporous form, bypasssing armor,
        carapaces, shields, and other forms of armor. The Shield of Ice adds an additional +2 bonus to the effective Defense
        Class of its wielder.
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_15">
        This spear and shield once belonged to Iolanthe of Argos, who was a noble woman from the late age of magic.
        She traveled widely throughout Mythika, but ultimately made her home in Midia, where she lead several key raids
        against the Stygians.
    </string>

    <!-- Mythic Armor Descriptions -->

    <string name="mytha_desc_1">
        These breastplates were forged by the gods to punish the haughty. Arrogant characters will see it as gleaming
        armor only which they are worthy to wear. Once it is put on, it will actually lower the character/'s EDC by -2.
        Only when the wearer has learned humility will he be able to remove the armor.
    </string>
    <string name="mytha_desc_2">
        When worn by an Impostaur, this impressive bronze bull\'s head-shaped mask-like helmet will make its wearer behave
        in a genuinely (as opposed to simulated) Minotaurian way, raising his Ferocity from Aggressive to Deadly, which
        will add +2 to the Impostaur's Initiative, +4 to his Melee and +8 to his Hits Total. The mask also provides the
        protection of a normal, non-magical helmet (+2 to the EDC) and has the same Enc value of 1.
    </string>
    <string name="mytha_desc_3">
        This beautiful magical helmet can be worn by any character but its magical properties will only awaken when worn
        by an Amazon of noble bearing (ie with a Personal Charisma of +1 or more)
    </string>
    <string name="mytha_desc_4">
        The magical virtues of this beautiful shield can only be used by warriors with a Grace of 13+. It allows its user
        to add his Grace bonus to his Defense Class (in addition to the regular +2 bonus given by the shield itself)
        and his Danger Evasion rolls against Petrification. This bonus is in addition of any other defensive bonus the character
        may have.
    </string>
    <string name="mytha_desc_5">
        This magical shield is a very rare, more powerful variant of the classic Aegis shield described in the Maze Masters Guide
        (P.37). While classic Aegises are made of magical bronze, these shields are made of shiny, mirror-like magical silver.
    </string>
    <string name="mytha_desc_6">
        This armor, which once belonged to the legendary hunter Eleon, was crafted during The Age of Magic by the Dryads who
        make their home in the forest south of the River Rhena. They gave this armor to Eleon to help him defend their lands
        against the ravages of the wild north.
    </string>
    <string name="mytha_desc_7">
        Wispy and pliable as a sheet of silk, this shirt gives the same protection as a normal breastplate (+2 to Defense
        Class), but has an effective Encumberance value of 0 (Yes, zero!)
    </string>
    <string name="mytha_desc_8">
        This breastplate adds a total of +6 to the wearer\'s effective Defense Class, but only as long as the wearer remains
        firmly standing on the ground once combat begins.
    </string>

    <!-- Mythic Miscellaneous Descriptions -->

    <string name="mythm_desc_1">
        The formula for the preparation of these wondrous ointments has been lost - and even if it was found or discovered
        it would probably not work, since the balms were concocted during the Age of Magic, a time of bygone enchantments and
        extinct wonders. They can only be found in ancient treasure rooms, temples and other similar places, usually in small
        pots or jars containing enough ointment for 1d6 application
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_2">
        This balm must be applied once per week to speed up the recovery of a wounded patient, doubling the amount of Hits
        recovered during the week.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_3">
        Each application of this balm restores 1 point of Might, Skill or Grace lost as consequence of grievous injury (see players
        manual, p23); such permanent damage is normally impossible to heal, even by magical means, which makes the Balm of Restoration
        the proverbial exception to the rule.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_4">
        This most potent balm can be used to restore the corpse of a recently deceased individual, essentially reversing the effects of
        decay and decomposition to allow a Divine Resurrection by a Sacred Healer.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_5">
        One single dose of this potion will make the drinker exceptionally watchful and alert for 1 hour, granting him a +2 bonus to
        Initiative and Danger Evasion.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_6">
        Each dose of this magical potion will make the drinker completely indefatigable for one hour, granting him the same benefits
        as the Divine Gift of Endurance (See Players Manual, p 31).
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_7">
        One dose of this potion makes the drinker completely immune to drowning, suffocation and other breathing hazards (including
        the effects of poison gases or fumes) for one hour.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_8">
        When sprinkled over one\'s person this subtle magical perfume will grant a bonus of +4 to that individual\'s seduction influence
        talent (M and M Companion, p 31).
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_9">
        If this seed is planted in the ground by a Priestess of Demeter, it will grow overnight into a bush that will produce a number of
        fruits equal to the Priestess' Grace Score
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_10">
        This silvery powder is used by Atlantean Sorcerers to regain some of their expended magical power without having to sleep for hours.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_11">
        These wands are more potent (and consequently rarer) versions of the Caduceus staff described in the Maze masters guide (p 42); each
        of them has the usual properties of a Caduceus as well as an additional magical virtual which can only be used by a True Sacred Healer.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_12">
        In addition to its other properties, this silver tipped Caduceus allows a Sacred Healer to cure blindness in an individual by spending
        3 Power Points.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_13">
        In addition to its other properties, this golden-tipped Caduceus allows a Sacred Healer to regenerate severed hands, missing legs and
        other mauled limbs. this comes at the cost of 6 Power Points and is not instantaneous, it will come back after a certain amount of time.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_14">
        In addition to its other properties, this obsidian tipped Caduceus has the power to restore Petrified individuals to life regardless of
        the time since they were petrified.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_15">
        This lordly wand can only be used by Nobles with a Grace of 13+. It allows the user to shoot forth bolts of bright magical light that do
        (1d6+Grace mod) in damage and a range max of 20.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_16">
        When used by a Priest of the appropriate deity, this magical sceptre allows the character to reduce the cost of his divine wrath power by
        2 Power Points.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_17">
        This amulet makes its wearer completely immune to the effects of the Sorcery powers of Confusion, Illusions, and Cloak.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_18">
        These amulets make their wearer immune to the venom of a specific family of creatures. They were supposedly crafted during the Age of Magic
        by the now extinct sorceresses of Thessalia, who helped the heroes of Minea and Umbria in their struggle against the Autarchs and their monstrous
        allies.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_19">
        This spider-shaped amulet makes its wearer immune to the effects of spider venom - including the poison of Giant Spiders, Daughters of Arachne and
        other arachnid creatures.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_20">
        This scorpion-shaped amulet makes its wearer immune to the effects of scorpion venom - including the poison of Giant Scorpions, Scorpion Folk and
        Manticores.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_21">
        This serpent-shaped amulet makes its wearer immune to the effects of snake venom - including the poison of Giant Snakes, Stygian Serpents and the
        Lamiae.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_22">
        This extremely rare amulet makes its wearer immune to the poison of Chimeras, whether it is secreted by a sting or a snakehead-like tail.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_23">
        This amulet heightens all its wearer\'s senses, giving him a +4 bonus to all perception rolls.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_24">
        This amulet boosts its wearer\'s rhetorical eloquence, granting him a +4 bonus to his Persuasion talent.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_25">
        When worn by a Sorcerer, this bull\'s head-shaped amulet raises the wearer\'s Mystic Strength by +4 when using his powers on a Minotaur or
        any other true Minotaur-kin.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_26">
        This magical pendant appears a 1" tall miniature of a strange satyr-like being, said to represent the mysterious god Kismet, an eastern deity
        of fate and fortune who is apparently very popular among the rogues and cutthroats of Khandaria, the notorious City of Thieves. it only works
        when used by a Thief, adding +2 to his Thievery bonus.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_27">
        This egg-sized, grey-blue stone will begin to glow whenever it is within 30 feet of any amount of gold, silver, or jewels worth at least 100
        silver pieces.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_28">
        When worn as an amulet, this nut-sized bloodstone offers an extremely effective but one-off defense against the Petrification powers of Gorgons,
        Basilisks and similar creatures.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_29">
        This amulet makes Sorcerers insensitive to the mysterious beauties of Nature and Poetry. In game terms it adds +4 to a Sorceror\'s Mystic Fortitude
        when defending against Nymphs and Lyrists.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_30">
        This ring allows the Priestesses of Hera to use their Divine Vision power at half cost; one Power Point instead of the usual two.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_31">
        This ring allows the Priestesses of Hestia to spend only two Power Points when using their Divine Vitality power (instead of the usual
        3).
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_32">
        This enchanted ring grants its wearer a +4 bonus to his Defense Class against all Missile Attacks. It has no effect against Melee attacks
        or special distance attacks.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_33">
        This amulet will automatically detect the presence of poison in any food, drink or other form within a 10\' radius. The wearer of the amulet
        will be able to tell precisely where the poison is but not its origin or its specific effects.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_34">
        This ring gives its wearer a +2 bonus to Mystic Fortitude when resisting magical powers which try to influence his actions or emotions.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_35">
        Rings of Sorcery appear as ordinary silver rings, set with different gemstones; those stones being Emerald, Topaz, Sapphire, and Ruby.
        each ring gives a Sorceror a +2 to his psychic gift and Mystic Strength and depending on the gemstone on the ring will give the sorceror
        an extra +2 bonus to one of his powers.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_36">
        This enchanted ring when put on makes it impossible for the wearer to lie about anything they are asked.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_37">
        The mystical virtues of these amulets can only be used by Priests of the appropriate deity. A Priest wearing the Sigil of his deity benefits
        from a permanent, full-power Divine Blessing. Thus, a Sigil of Athena worn by one of her Priestesses would grant her a +2 bonus to the Defense
        Class, Danger Evasion, Mystic Fortitude and Personal Charisma.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_38">
        These magical pendants of primitive craftsmanship have been carved in bone, horn or ivory in the shape of various miniature animals.
        Each talisman confers to its wearer a different ability reflecting the symbolic virtues associated with the animal.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_39">
        This magical belt allows devotees of Hestia with a Grace of 13+ to add their Grace bonus to their Defense Class and Mystic Fortitude
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_40">
        This belt reduces its wearers starting Encumbrance score to 5 instead of 10.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_41">
        This magical item looks like an ordinary hunting cap, adorned with a long feather. It gives its wearer an unerring ability to always find
        the direction of the north, even when lost underground.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_42">
        This magical cloak allows its wearer to blend with his surroundings, much like creatures with the Camouflage special ability.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_43">
        When the hood of this cloak is put on its wearer\'s head, he becomes completely unrecognizable even to his closest acquaintances.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_44">
        This enchanted, beautifully woven cloak of the finest purple adds +2 to it\'s wearer's Personal Charisma; this bonus is doubled for
        Nobles.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_45">
        This magical garment seems to be made of the darkest shadow, woven into the form of a cloak, When worn in a dark or shadowy environment,
        it adds a +4 to the wearer's stealth rolls as well as to the target number of all detection rolls.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_46">
        This coronet can only be used by Priestesses of Aphrodite with a Grace of 13+, allowing the wearer to add her Grace bonus to her Spiritual
        Aura.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_47">
        This coronet can only be used by Priestesses of Hera, revealing their inner beauty in a truly wondrous manner. It allows the wearer to add her Spiritual
        Aura to her Grace score, up to a score of 21.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_48">
        This coronet can normally can be used by especially Graceful (Grace 13+) Priestesses of a particular goddess, to whom the coronet is explicitly dedicated.
        it allows the wearer to add her Grace bonus to her basic Defense Class and to her Mystic Fortitude, no helmet combination.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_49">
        This plain-looking metal headband gives its wearer perfect night vision, negating any penalty to attack and detection rolls caused by darkness (including
        underground and magical darkness, such as that created by a Cloak of Shadow
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_50">
        This bright red cloak is cut in the finest (and utterly indestructible) magical wool. It gives a +2 bonus to its wearer\'s EDC against all Melee attacks made
        by Minotaurs and other true Minotaur-kin, but will infuriate the Minotaurian monster who will turn it's attention to only the wearer
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_51">
        These sandals always come in pairs. They can only be worn by hunters with a Grace of 13+, giving a Hunting bonus equal to their Grace mod.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_52">
        These sandals always come in pairs and can only be used by characters with a Grace of 13+, allowing their wearer to add his Grace mod to his
        Initiative score.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_53">
        These nondescript, ordinary-looking sandals add +4 to their wearer\'s stealth rolls and to the target number of detection rolls made to spot, hear
        or even track him. If one sandal is worn, the bonus is only +2.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_54">
        When worn by a Nymph of any kin, this magical silken scarf belt adds +2 to her Odyllic Charm and Mystic Strength when using her powers of
        Nature's Seduction.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_55">
        The magical virtues of this tunic can only be used by Hunters with a Grace of 13+, allowing them to add their Grace mod to their Hunting Score.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_56">
        This beautiful, wondrously woven tunic adds +1 to the wearer\'s Grace mod. It comes in both male and female version, with a wide choice of absolutely
        divine colors.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_57">
        This magical leather tunic is made from the flayed skin of a Minotaur. A Minotaur (or any other true Minotaur kin) will never attempt a Grapple
        attack against a person wearing such a tunic.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_58">
        When worn by a Shapeshifter, this magical tunic always reappears on the character\'s body if he so wishes. Thus, a Shapeshifter wearing this tunic could
        turn into any animal form then revert to his human form, wearing the tunic again, the tunic is also virtually indestructible and can change color.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_59">
        This leather wristband gives its wearer a +2 bonus to Initiative and Missile scores when using a bow. Wearing one Wristband of Archery on each wrist will not
        result in a higher bonus.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_60">
        This magical lamp from the mysterious Land of the Sun can only be used by Elementalists with Fire powers. It allows the magician to summon a flamoid servant.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_61">
        Legends say these disposable mythic items were crafted by Apollo himself as a "Break up Gift" for a group of charming Naiads with whom had dallied in his playful youth.
        When a nymph looks in the mirror it acquires a number of charges equal to her Grace mod. Spending one charge will allow the nymph to regain
        1d6 power points without having to meld with nature
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_62">
        This opalescent, unbreakable, head sized magical sphere can only be used by Elementalists with air powers. it allows the magician to summan an eolian that will
        obey all his orders.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_63">
        The sound of this magical harp has a deep inspiring quality which adds +2 to a Lyrist\'s Orphic Voice and Mystic Fortitude when playing magnitude songs
        this increases the effect of the songs and their range.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_64">
        The sound of this magical harp has an enchanted, appeasing quality which adds +2 to a Lyrist\'s Orphic Voice and Mystic Strength when used to play any magnitude songs.
        This affects their effectiveness, and their range.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_65">
        This item looks like a hunting olifant carve from the horn of a huge bull. Only persons with an above average Might (13+) can blow it properly: if blown by such an individual
        the olifant will produce a sound that will make any minotaur within the sound range retreat in fear.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_66">
        The enlightened elementalist is a scholarly work that was compiled in the Age of Magic by the various Elementalist schools in the distant city of Ishtar. The complete collection
        consists of seven clay tablets and is written with consummate erudition in the classical Hazarian of Ishtar as used by the Wizard-Kings of the Second Age. An elementalist  who is
        skilled with a certain element will gain 100 Wisdom points for reading the appropriate tablet, 200 points if the tablet is on his primary element. the lost 7th tablet has valuable information
        on all the elements that will give 300 Wisdom points to any elementalist.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_67">
        The Heresies of Zenon is considered the most controversial literary works ever produced by Zenon the Philosopher. These aroused hostility from many quarters and disgust from the gods themselves.
        Magicians who read these writings will gain 200 points but as a consequence will not be able to become a divine agent or lose their status as a divine agent.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_68">
        Easily the most famed of Midian Mariners, Hanno the Navigator\'s detailed ship-logs gave details of all his many voyages around the Middle Sea and even beyond the Bronze Gates, exploring the farthest
        coasts of Charybdis. the logs are numbered I to VII. Any Mariner who gains the first four scrolls will gain 100 Experience points per scroll, and 200 points for the remaining scrolls.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_69">
        The Pronouncements of Telphos contained much of the distilled wisdom of the philosopher telphos, reading these scrolls give 100 wisdom points per scroll.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_70">
        the seven scrolls of proteus  is an incredible set of scrolls that supposedly contain traditions that in part go right back to proteus, the father of the proteusian family
        of humans including the mineans and the first humans to be able to shapeshift. reading these scrolls will give 100 wisdom points for the first four and 200 for the remaining scrolls.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_71">
        The tome of many tongues is a wondrous work that is capable of translating a piece of speech from one language into two others.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_72">
        the seven unmatched scrolls of medical insight collect the complete works of the greatest sacred healer of the age of magic, Hippokratos.
        any sacred healer who reads the first four will gain 100 Wisdom points and 200 for the remaining scrolls.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_73">
        The poet hesidos is regarded as the greatest storyteller that the island of seriphos has ever produced. any lyrist from seriphos who reads the first four gain 100 wisdom points, and 200 for
        the remaining, any other lyrist only gets half of the points.
    </string>

</resources>

