<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <!-- Mythic Item Descriptions -->
    <!-- Mythic Weapon Descriptions -->

    <string name="mythw_desc_1">
        These two items are always found together;
        they were obviously part of some ancient panoply from a forgotten time.
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_2">
        This black-bladed dagger will only reveal its magical powers when used
        by a person with a Luck of 13+.
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_3">
        The magical virtues of this bow can only be used by the most Graceful warriors
        or specialists (i.e. those with a grace of 13+).
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_4">
        In addition to their normal damage, these arrows cause the target to either fall
        in love or become jealous of another person or creature - unless the target makes
        a Mystic Fortitude saving roll.
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_5">
        This javelin allows Graceful Warriors (i.e. those with a Grace Score of 13+)
        to add their Grace bonus to both their Missile attack roll and damage roll.
        Note, however that the Javelin of Heartbreak cannot be used as a melee spear. (Enc=1)
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_6">
        The magical virtues of this spear can only be used by classic Amazons (or by alternate
        Amazons with a grace of 13+). It allows the wielder to add her Grace bonus to her
        Initiative and Melee attack roll when the soear is used to Charge into Battle. (Enc=2)
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_7">
        This magical spear can only be properly used by Hunters; its magical properties can only
        operate against Beasts and Monsters. When used in Melee, it allows the Hunter to benefit
        from his Skill-based damage bonus; when thrown as a javelin, it doubles this damage bonus (Enc=2)
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_8">
        This magical spear grants its user a bonus to his Melee attacks and damage rolls when used
        against Monsters. This bonus varies according to the size of the creature (the bigger the better!):
        +1 if Medium or smaller, +2 if Large and +4 if Gigantic.
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_9">
        Created as a gift for the Noble divine agents of Aphrodite, this sword can only be used by Graceful
        warriors (i.e. with a Grace of 13+), allowing them to add their Grace mod to damage rolls (Enc=1)
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_10">
        This ancient magical bronze sword grants a +2 bonus to Melee and damage when used against Minotaurs
        and other true Minotaur-kin, as well as against bulls including Giant and Magical ones but excluding Bronze Animates
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_11">
        These ancient short swords were used by the men of King Letos, first monarch of Thena in their battles against the ophidian
        minions of Thulsos
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_12">
        This unique, beautifully-crafted and indestructible two-handed battle axe was forged at the dawn of the Age of Magic as a
        symbol of royalty for the kings of the Uroks - the creatures humans prefer to refer to as Golden Minotaurs.
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_13">
        This weapon can launch as many Fiery Darts (as per the Elementalist power of the same name) per day as the character\'s
        Melee mod. it can also be used as a normal sword.
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_14">
        The spear of Vapor when thrown by a character with a Skill of 13 or higher, turns into a vaporous form, bypasssing armor,
        carapaces, shields, and other forms of armor. The Shield of Ice adds an additional +2 bonus to the effective Defense
        Class of its wielder.
    </string>
    <string name="mythw_desc_15">
        This spear and shield once belonged to Iolanthe of Argos, who was a noble woman from the late age of magic.
        She traveled widely throughout Mythika, but ultimately made her home in Midia, where she lead several key raids
        against the Stygians.
    </string>

    <!-- Mythic Armor Descriptions -->

    <string name="mytha_desc_1">
        These breastplates were forged by the gods to punish the haughty. Arrogant characters will see it as gleaming
        armor only which they are worthy to wear. Once it is put on, it will actually lower the character/'s EDC by -2.
        Only when the wearer has learned humility will he be able to remove the armor.
    </string>
    <string name="mytha_desc_2">
        When worn by an Impostaur, this impressive bronze bull\'s head-shaped mask-like helmet will make its wearer behave
        in a genuinely (as opposed to simulated) Minotaurian way, raising his Ferocity from Aggressive to Deadly, which
        will add +2 to the Impostaur's Initiative, +4 to his Melee and +8 to his Hits Total. The mask also provides the
        protection of a normal, non-magical helmet (+2 to the EDC) and has the same Enc value of 1.
    </string>
    <string name="mytha_desc_3">
        This beautiful magical helmet can be worn by any character but its magical properties will only awaken when worn
        by an Amazon of noble bearing (ie with a Personal Charisma of +1 or more)
    </string>
    <string name="mytha_desc_4">
        The magical virtues of this beautiful shield can only be used by warriors with a Grace of 13+. It allows its user
        to add his Grace bonus to his Defense Class (in addition to the regular +2 bonus given by the shield itself)
        and his Danger Evasion rolls against Petrification. This bonus is in addition of any other defensive bonus the character
        may have.
    </string>
    <string name="mytha_desc_5">
        This magical shield is a very rare, more powerful variant of the classic Aegis shield described in the Maze Masters Guide
        (P.37). While classic Aegises are made of magical bronze, these shields are made of shiny, mirror-like magical silver.
    </string>
    <string name="mytha_desc_6">
        This armor, which once belonged to the legendary hunter Eleon, was crafted during The Age of Magic by the Dryads who
        make their home in the forest south of the River Rhena. They gave this armor to Eleon to help him defend their lands
        against the ravages of the wild north.
    </string>
    <string name="mytha_desc_7">
        Wispy and pliable as a sheet of silk, this shirt gives the same protection as a normal breastplate (+2 to Defense
        Class), but has an effective Encumberance value of 0 (Yes, zero!)
    </string>
    <string name="mytha_desc_8">
        This breastplate adds a total of +6 to the wearer\'s effective Defense Class, but only as long as the wearer remains
        firmly standing on the ground once combat begins.
    </string>

    <!-- Mythic Miscellaneous Descriptions -->

    <string name="mythm_desc_1">
        The formula for the preparation of these wondrous ointments has been lost - and even if it was found or discovered
        it would probably not work, since the balms were concocted during the Age of Magic, a time of bygone enchantments and
        extinct wonders. They can only be found in ancient treasure rooms, temples and other similar places, usually in small
        pots or jars containing enough ointment for 1d6 application
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_2">
        This balm must be applied once per week to speed up the recovery of a wounded patient, doubling the amount of Hits
        recovered during the week.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_3">
        Each application of this balm restores 1 point of Might, Skill or Grace lost as consequence of grievous injury (see players
        manual, p23); such permanent damage is normally impossible to heal, even by magical means, which makes the Balm of Restoration
        the proverbial exception to the rule.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_4">
        This most potent balm can be used to restore the corpse of a recently deceased individual, essentially reversing the effects of
        decay and decomposition to allow a Divine Resurrection by a Sacred Healer.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_5">
        One single dose of this potion will make the drinker exceptionally watchful and alert for 1 hour, granting him a +2 bonus to
        Initiative and Danger Evasion.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_6">
        Each dose of this magical potion will make the drinker completely indefatigable for one hour, granting him the same benefits
        as the Divine Gift of Endurance (See Players Manual, p 31).
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_7">
        One dose of this potion makes the drinker completely immune to drowning, suffocation and other breathing hazards (including
        the effects of poison gases or fumes) for one hour.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_8">
        When sprinkled over one\'s person this subtle magical perfume will grant a bonus of +4 to that individual\'s seduction influence
        talent (M and M Companion, p 31).
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_9">
        If this seed is planted in the ground by a Priestess of Demeter, it will grow overnight into a bush that will produce a number of
        fruits equal to the Priestess' Grace Score
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_10">
        This silvery powder is used by Atlantean Sorcerers to regain some of their expended magical power without having to sleep for hours.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_11">
        These wands are more potent (and consequently rarer) versions of the Caduceus staff described in the Maze masters guide (p 42); each
        of them has the usual properties of a Caduceus as well as an additional magical virtual which can only be used by a True Sacred Healer.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_12">
        In addition to its other properties, this silver tipped Caduceus allows a Sacred Healer to cure blindness in an individual by spending
        3 Power Points.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_13">
        In addition to its other properties, this golden-tipped Caduceus allows a Sacred Healer to regenerate severed hands, missing legs and
        other mauled limbs. this comes at the cost of 6 Power Points and is not instantaneous, it will come back after a certain amount of time.
    </string>
    <string name="mythm_desc_14">
        In addition to its other properties, this obsidian tipped Caduceus has the power to restore Petrified individuals to life regardless of
        the time since they were petrified.
    </string>
</resources>

