<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <!-- Spell Descriptions -->
    <!-- Priest Spells -->
    <string name="priest_1_desc">
        With this power, a Priest may place his deity’s
        blessing upon an individual (including himself). To
        Bless someone, the Priest must be able to touch the
        head, heart or shoulder of the chosen individual.
    </string>
    <string name="priest_2_desc">
        With this power, a Priest may ask his deity to send
        him a vision related to a specific person, place or
        situation. Depending on the circumstances, these
        visions may come from the past, the present or
        even the future – but visions of the future often take
        a symbolic form that make them difficult to interpret.
    </string>
    <string name="priest_3_desc">
        With this power, a Priest may call on his deity’s
        supernatural might to instantly heal an individual’s
        wounds and injuries, infusing him with divine vitality.
        The Priest may use this power on any person or
        creature he can touch, including himself.
    </string>
    <string name="priest_4_desc">
        This power allows a Priest to bestow a spectacular
        ability to a chosen individual (including himself).
        This ability varies according to the deity’s sphere of
        influence, as shown below. The effects of a Divine
        Gift may be combined with those a Blessing but are
        much shorter, lasting for a number of battle rounds
        equal to the Priest’s Spiritual Aura.
    </string>
    <string name="priest_5_desc">
        This power allows the Priest to strike his enemies
        with a bolt of pure spiritual energy.
    </string>
    <string name="priest_6_desc">
        With this very spectacular power, a Priest may ask
        for a direct intervention by his deity. This requires
        the expenditure of 6 Power points, followed by a
        percentile roll to see if the deity actually answers.
        The chance of success of this percentile roll is equal
        to 2% per level of the Priest. If the % roll fails, the
        deity does not answer and the Power has been
        spent in vain: the Priest may try again but will have
        to spend 6 Power points before every new attempt.
    </string>

    <!-- Nymph Spells -->
    <string name="nymph_1_desc">
        This Gift enables a Nymph to entrance a mortal,
        animal or monster with her preternatural charm. To
        use this power, the Nymph must be able to see (and
        be seen by) her intended target, who is allowed a
        Mystic Fortitude roll to resist. The power has a
        range equal to the Nymph’s Odylic Charm x 10’.
    </string>
    <string name="nymph_2_desc">
        This Gift allows a Nymph to alter her appearance:
        her hair and eye color, skin hue, facial features etc.
        It does not enable her to change her physical form
        but can make her look (and sound) like someone
        else, provided this someone is a humanoid female
        of roughly similar size.
    </string>
    <string name="nymph_3_desc">
        This Gift enables a Nymph to instantly heal an
        individual’s wounds and injuries by the power of
        their own preternatural life force. The Nymph may
        heal any being she can touch, including herself.
    </string>
    <string name="nymph_4_desc">
        With this Gift (and a simple kiss), a Nymph may
        attune another person with her natural environment.
        These effects last for a number of hours equal to the
        Nymph’s Odylic Charm
    </string>
    <string name="nymph_5_desc">
        With this Gift, a Nymph may use her kiss to bestow
        a curse on a chosen victim. The exact form and
        effects of the curse depend on the Nymph’s kin.
    </string>
    <string name="nymph_6_desc">
        With this power, a Nymph can summon spectacular
        manifestations of Nature’s might, control elements
        and bring inanimate things to life!
    </string>

    <!-- Lyrist Spells -->
    <string name="lyrist_1_desc">
        This song grants a +2 bonus to one of the
        characters D20 modifiers (Melee Missile or one of
        the four saving rolls) of the Lyrist's choice.
    </string>
    <string name="lyrist_2_desc">
        This Song can be used to free other characters or
        creatures from Enslavement by a Sorcerer or
        creature with Psychic Power.
    </string>
    <string name="lyrist_3_desc">
        This song enables a Lyrist to entrance a mortal,
        animal or monster with his swelling music.
    </string>
    <string name="lyrist_4_desc">
        Those who benefit from the effects of this song
        immediately heal 1D6 Hits (without exceeding their
        usual maximum). It may affect up to (Lyrist’s Orphic
        Voice bonus) individuals and takes one entire
        minute (10 battle rounds) to execute.
    </string>
    <string name="lyrist_5_desc">
        This song is imbued with the power of rage and
        anger. Like the Song of Soothing, it takes effect and
        must be powered as soon as the Lyrist begins to
        play (see Song of Soothing above). It may affect up
        to (Lyrist’s Orphic Voice bonus) targets and has a
        range of (Orphic Voice x 10’), like all other Songs.
    </string>
    <string name="lyrist_6_desc">
        Inspired by the prophetic gifts of Orpheus, the first
        Lyrist, this Song allows a Lyrist to perceive and
        reveal the hidden patterns of Fate.
    </string>

    <!-- Sorceror Spells -->
    <string name="sorceror_1_desc">
        This power enables a Sorcerer to disorient and
        befuddle the mind of another person, animal or
        monster. It has a range of Psychic Gift x 10’ and
        may be resisted with a Mystic Fortitude saving roll.
    </string>
    <string name="sorceror_2_desc">
        With this power, a Sorcerer affects the sensory
        perception of an individual to make him believe he
        sees or hears things that are not there… To use this
        power, the Sorcerer must be able to see the
        individual he wishes to affect and must be within
        (Psychic Gift x 10’) of his chosen target.
    </string>
    <string name="sorceror_3_desc">
        This power gives a Sorcerer the power to conceal
        his presence to the minds of others, even if he is
        standing in plain sight.
    </string>
    <string name="sorceror_4_desc">
        This power allows a Sorcerer to dominate the will of
        another individual. It requires direct eye contact and
        thus can only be used against a single target. In
        addition, its range is limited to 5 times the Sorcerer’s
        Psychic Gift in feet (i.e. half of the usual range for
        ranged powers). The victim is allowed a Mystic
        Fortitude roll to fight off the Sorcerer’s domination. If
        the target fails to resist, he will be forced to obey the
        Sorcerer’s commands for a number of rounds equal
        to the Sorcerer’s Psychic Gift.
    </string>
    <string name="sorceror_5_desc">
        With this power, a Sorcerer may strike his foes with
        an invisible bolt of pure sorcerous energy.
    </string>
    <string name="sorceror_6_desc">
        This spell is a permanent form of Compelling. It can
        only be used on a victim under a Compelling spell
        cast by the same Sorcerer. Thus, each attempt at
        Enslavement will actually cost 10 Power points: 4
        for the Compelling and 6 for the Enslavement itself.
    </string>

    <!-- Elementalist Fire Spells -->
    <string name="fire_1_desc">
        With this power, an Elementalist summons forth a
        bolt of pure fire to hurl at his enemies. This fiery
        attack requires no attack roll but may be dodged
        with a Danger Evasion saving roll.
    </string>
    <string name="fire_2_desc">
        This power allows the Elementalist to conjure a
        man-sized ball of fiery flame that he can move by
        mental command.
    </string>
    <string name="fire_3_desc">
        With this power, an Elementalist causes an eruption
        of volcanic fire that engulfs his foes in burning
        sorrow for a number of battle rounds equal to the
        Elementalist’s Mastery bonus.
    </string>

    <!-- Elementalist Water Spells -->
    <string name="water_1_desc">
        This power enables an Elementalist to cause water
        to spout mightily from his hand. He may direct this
        torrent automatically towards any target within a
        range of (Mastery x 10’). A character or creature hit
        by the torrent must pass a Danger Evasion roll or be
        thrown back 2D6 feet and knocked down. Large
        creatures are only thrown back 1D6 feet and
        Gigantic ones are unaffected.
    </string>
    <string name="water_2_desc">
        With this power, an Elementalist can flood an area
        with vigorously churning water, causing all within to
        be hindered. It has a range of (Mastery x 50’) and a
        radius of (Mastery x 10’).
    </string>
    <string name="water_3_desc">
        This power can only be used in the presence of a
        large body of water (at least 20 yards across). It
        allows the Elementalist to summon a giant tentaclelike
        appendage of water ending in a huge fist.
    </string>

    <!-- Elementalist Air Spells -->
    <string name="air_1_desc">
        This power enables an Elementalist to cause the
        wind to whip around the target, increasing his EDC
        vs Missile attacks. This power has a range of
        (Elementalist’s Mastery x 10’) and may be used on
        a group, up to a number of individuals equal to the
        Elementalist’s Mastery bonus, as long as all the
        intended targets are within range.
    </string>
    <string name="air_2_desc">
        The target of this power is ravaged by a whirlwind
        which lasts for a number of rounds equal to the
        magician’s Mastery bonus.
    </string>
    <string name="air_3_desc">
        With this power, an Elementalist can summon a
        furious gigantic whirlwind that scatters his foes like
        leaves in the wind. The gale can be created
        anywhere within sight of the magician and has a
        radius equal to (Mastery x 10’).
    </string>

    <!-- Elementalist Earth Spells -->
    <string name="earth_1_desc">
        This power enables an Elementalist to cause stone
        hands to erupt from the ground and seize an
        enemy’s legs. It has a range of (Mastery x 10’).
        Gigantic creatures cannot be affected by this power.
        The designated target may make a Danger Evasion
        roll to escape the grasp of the Hands of Stone.
        Once he has been grappled, however, he may only
        try to break free with a feat of strength.
    </string>
    <string name="earth_2_desc">
        This power works on any living being the magician
        can touch (including himself); it infuses the recipient
        with the essence of bronze, greatly increasing his
        strength and resistance to damage.
    </string>
    <string name="earth_3_desc">
        This powerful spell allows an Elementalist to
        animate a Large stone statue, bringing it to life. In
        order to use this power, the Elementalist must be
        within (Mastery x 10’) of the statue.
    </string>
</resources>